Welcome to this video. In this video we
will be discussing about how do we use
tools in the agent framework. So
basically the agent will automatically
call the tool when a conversation
requests it. For in this particular
program the user is asking hey what is
the weather like in Portland? It cannot
use the historical data rather like it
has to get the real-time data. In order
to do that it it needs to make a call to
the tool. the tool will get the you know
current data and pass it to the agent.
So in this two-step process one we have
to define our tool. So in this case I
have defined a function called get
weather. It takes a location as input
and right now like it you know it uses
the hardcoded values here but in a
production environment rather like you
will be getting the input from the LLM
and like make a call to the
corresponding API get the results back
and pass it to the LLM. Now we have
defined the tool here and we need to
register the tool. So when we create the
agent, we have to pass the tool
information to the agent. So the agent
can use that. Right? So now let go to
the visual studio and execute the code.
This is the typical code that we always
uses except the tool definition and it's
a registration. So we go in a loop, get
the input from the user, pass it to the
llm and print the value. So now let me
go ahead and run the program. So this is
going to be my ninth program. Let's run
it. Let's pass the input. What is the
weather like in Portland? So what it
what the agent it's going to do is that
it will extract the city name and pass
it to the tool here the weather tool and
it will print the result in a moment. It
will respond back to us. So it will be
in this particular format. Right? So the
weather in this particular location it's
whatever is that some random value that
we are printing it. Right. So now if I
say like what is the weather like in
London? This is not a realtime data
rather like it just uses the hardcoded
value that we have. Right. Just to
demonstrate like how do we use the tool.
So if you in a real world so you will
you know make a change here. You will
make a call to the weather API pass the
information that you received and get
the results back. That's how it works.
Right now let me quit this program. Let
me clear the console. Now in this
program like we are using the Azure A
agent client and pass the tool
information. So this is a temporary
agent right now let's see like how do we
create the permanent agent and use the
tool. So program we will be using the
project client to create the agent.
However like we have not passed the tool
information you could technically pass
the tool information rather I wanted to
showcase how do we use the chart agent
and pass the tool information here. So
we created a agent and we created the
instance of the Azure Agent client and
pass that instance to the chart agent
here and pass the tool information. So
in our previous video we have used the
tool information uh in like when we
create the agent we have passed the tool
information but this time around we are
passing it to the chart agent. Both are
same. So whenever you have a Python tool
you can very well pass it to the chart
agent. Rest of the program will be same.
So we'll be going in a loop asking the
input from the user and pass it to the
agent. Now let me go ahead and run the
program. So this is going to be the 10th
program. Now let me ask the same
question here. So we are creating a
permanent agent. Now let me ask the
agent. What is the weather like in port
Portland? Again the process is going to
be the same, right? So it is going to
return the same result or the similar
result. Now let me ask the other
question as well. So it is again going
to be u making a call to the tool and
responding back to us right. So now let
me quit. Uh intentionally I deleted the
agent. I don't want to keep any agent
running. Now let's move forward. So so
far like we have discussed how do we use
a single tool. But what happens like
when you wanted to use a multiple tool,
right? So here like this program we will
be using three different tools. The
weather tool, calculate tool and there
is also going to be a time tool. So the
registration it is going to be same. So
when when you create a you know instance
of the chart agent you pass all the
tools that you wanted the agent to use
it right. So let's register the tool.
Let me go ahead and run the program
and uh let me ask the questions.
So first we will be checking the weather
tool. So what is the weather in New
York? Then we will be making a [snorts]
call to the call plate tool.
Then finally we will also test the time
to
let it respond back. Now let me also
pass the time specific information.
So now as you see here it doesn't have
to be a single tool rather like you can
have multiple tools associated with the
agent. Now let's see like how do we use
the open API specification. So now let's
assume that there is a open API you know
published somewhere and you want the
agent to use that right now we will see
how do we use that to do that we need to
use something called open API tool here
so now if you see here the process again
going to be the same here so first you
have to create a open API tool and pass
the name under the specification. So
specification if you see here we are
loading the specification. So from this
particular JSON file. So if you see here
I downloaded the open APA specification
I kept it in this particular folder.
This is my open APA specification. So
whenever we make a like these are all
the functions it does support right. So
there are quite a few functions it does
support. So the currency and the name
information it does support. So now if I
just go back to the open API
specification, I just load that
specification
uh into this particular object and pass
it to the open API tool. Now I have this
tool with me ready. So authentication if
a open API needs any authentication, you
can variable pass the authentication.
But in this case, this particular open
API specification or a rest endpoint
doesn't need any authentication. So I'm
just using the anonymous authentication
here. Now we have this open API tool.
It's just we just need to register with
the agent. So if I just come over here,
this is how you will register your open
API tools here. So now let's go ahead
and run the program. Let me create the
console here.
Let me ask what is the name of name and
the population of a country that uses
the currency observation INR. So now
what it is going to do is that it is
going to use the tool the open API tool
and it is going to return the result. So
as you see here it just returned India
boot on with all the information. So
this is how you can use open API as a
tool in the agent.
Now let's move forward and discuss about
the vector store. I want to do is that I
want to build a agent use my own
document to respond back to the user
queries. So if you see here I have a
document about the London travel. So
what I want to do is that I want to
upload this document uh to the Azure
Aoundary and then like my agent should
uh use this document to respond back to
the user queries. So let's see how do we
do that. So before I do that let me quit
this existing program. Let me clear the
console as well.
First we need to create a vector store.
So if you see here, I'm reading this
file information and creating a data set
here. And then like once the data set is
created, then I will be creating a
vector store. Let's go to the portal and
see how do we do that.
So if you come over to the portal under
the data section data and index section,
this is where we will be uploading a
data set. Once the data set is created
then we will be creating a vector store
that will internally will create a index
for us. So again like we will be using
the project client to upload the file
basically like that will add the file
into the data set and based on which we
will be creating a vector store. Now
when we have the vector store then we
will be using a tool called hosted file
search tool right. So uh that takes the
vector store ID. So if you see here
first I'm creating a vector store. Now I
have the vector store id that I will be
passing it to this particular tool. The
tool again it's associated with the
chart client agent. So in rest of the
program we'll be seeing. So if you just
come over here we are just going through
the loop and we will be asking some
questions to the agent. With that let
let me go ahead and run the program. So
this is going to be the 30th program.
Now I will be asking can you provide the
recommendation right? So can you provide
the recommendation? So let me copy that.
Let me paste it here.
Now let me enter that information here.
Let me maximize this. So if you see here
first what we have done we uploaded the
file. We uploaded the file and like we
received the uh uh ID and based on which
we created a vector store. Now the
information like the vector store
information it's passed to the agent and
the agent will be using the same. So if
I just come over here this is giving me
some uh places to visit, accommodation,
transport information. So if you just
come over here you will see the exact
information here. So all of if you go to
the portal you will see the index
information here. If you click on that
you will see the file name here. So this
is associated with this London PDF. And
if you just go back and look at the
vector store you will see the vector
store information here. It will populate
in a moment. So if you see here you will
see this information here. Right? Again
like this is also associated with the
same f. And if you go to the agents, the
agents that we created file search
agent. If you click on that, you will
see the file that we upload and it's
called the travel guide. Now let's go to
the visual studio again. If you just how
you can use your own file with the
agent. Now let me quit this program. Now
let's move forward and discuss how do we
use something called Azure search. So
basically like it's this is going to be
pretty similar, right? So, so in this
project what we have done we have
uploaded a file into the agent. This is
working but then like at enterprise
level you want to use Azure search
basically like you will be creating your
own index for your own project and then
like upload all the relevant content
into that particular uh index right so
in that purpose you basically will be
using Azure search rather than directly
uploading your file into the agent. So
now let's see like how do we do that. So
before I do that let me go to the portal
again. So the management center this is
the like we have connected our Azure a
search. So this is the name of the
search. So if I go to the search go to
the search explorer I will be using this
index and if I look for a city something
like Paris then it is going to give me
some information. So this is what I want
to use in my agent. So now let's go
back. So if we just come over here what
we are doing here is that we are using a
project client get all the connections
and like we will find or filter the
connection by type jurya search get the
connection ID. Now we will have a
connection ID and we will be using that
connection ID to create a tool. So there
is a tool type called jury search that
takes the uh search connection ID and
the index name. If I just go back here.
So this is the index name that we are
using it here. query type when you
create a index you will be choosing the
query type. Now let's go ahead and
create the chart agent. So we just
created a chart agent passing the agent
information here. Now we have predefined
the user input. We are not going to ask
for input rather like we have predefined
input. So it says that find the detailed
information about London like I think I
have uploaded five different cities in
my previous video. So like cell London
it's one of the city uh that is uploaded
into the a search. Now on top of the
regular uh response I'm also trying to
get the citation. So that means that we
will show like which document this is
coming from right. So we will also try
to display that information. Finally we
will see this is completed. Let me clear
the console. Now let me go ahead and run
the program again.
Now this is not going to ask the user
input. The reason is that as said like
the user input it's already hardcoded
here. So find the detailed information
about London. So this this will get
printed here. Right? So this is how you
can use Azure AE search with your agent
framework. We have this code interpreter
tool. Whenever you wanted to write and
execute a Python code, you can use this
particular tool. So let me clear the
console here. So if you see here there
is a tool definition called code
interpreter tool that is part of this
particular package we can import and
like when we define the agent all we
need to do is that we have to say to
code interpreter definition. So which
means that the tool will be associated
with this particular agent and go and
ask the agent to write a Python program.
If you see here like we have a
predefined user input saying like write
a fibon series up to n and like we are
passing n as a 10 right now with that
let me go ahead and run the program 15.
So it is just going to take the user
input and pass it to the agent. Agent
will write and execute the python and
will return the result. So now as you
see here it does return the fibon series
for us. So now in this video we
discussed a lot about tools. How do we
define the tools? How do we associate
the tools? And how do we use the tools
with your to know more about tools? You
can refer the Microsoft agent framework
documentation. Not only for tools but
any any specific topic you are
interested in, you can always refer back
to this particular documentation. And uh
you can also look into the samples
provided here by Microsoft. time to time
they will add or you know update the
existing samples. So you can always
refer back to this particular repo for
any code samples like most of my samples
are coming from this particular
repository only.
Upcoming video we will discuss about
thread and state management. Thank you
for watching this video.